Muhammed Sarbast

hsarbast20@gmail.com • +964 750 890 6562

github.com/HamaSarbast-1997/ • linkedin.com/in/muhammed-sarbast/ • muhammed.dev

Summary Statement

Software engineer with bachelor's in software engineering and 2+ years' experience specializing in backend development, database design, and API development, and enjoys customizing all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience

Backend Developer / Full-time

Kernel LTD, Erbil, Kurdistan

June 2022 - Present

- Designing algorithms and flowcharts to create new software programs and systems.
- Troubleshooting, debugging, maintaining and improving existing software.
- Tested, coded, reviewed, and delivered software with 100% on-time rec.
- Observing user feedback to recommended improvements to existing software products
- Implemented RESTful API and admin dashboard using NodeJs and ReactJs for management system, websites, mobile applications

Full-Stack Developer / Full-time

Lucid Source LTD, Erbil, Kurdistan

May 2021 – May 2022

- Built several dashboards and API for several websites and platform applications, and developed a custom management system throughout my time in the company.
- lead the team in modernizing the code base from ASP to NodeJs and lead fresh developers to improve their skills.
- Organizing and assigning tasks and making clean architecture.
- Implemented several API microservices in Node.js.
- Collaborating with management, departments and customers to identify end-user requirements and specifications

Full-Stack Developer / Part-time

Technobase, Erbil, Kurdistan

August 2021 - July 2022 5:00 PM To 10:00 PM

- Implemented RESTful API server for application which is service application(pesha.krd).
- Compiling and assessing user feedback to improve software performance.
- Producing efficient and elegant code based on requirements.
- Implemented RESTful API and Dashboard using NodeJs and ReactJs for websites.
- Developed an easy-to-use dashboard using ReactJs for custom real estate management systems.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering in Software Engineering

University of Salahaddin College of Engineering, Erbil, Kurdistan.

2018 - 2021

Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, MySQL Server, NoSQL.

Services: Firebase, Twilio.

Technologies: Node.js, React.js(Antdesign), Knex.js, Sequelize, Prisma, MongoDb, Mongoose,

Tools: VSCode, MySQL Workbench, MongoDb Compass, Github, Gitlab, Notion, Agile methodology, Postman, MS Office

+2 years' experience in backend development

- Excellent knowledge in the software development life cycle.
- Strong problem-solving skills.
- Strong knowledge in Object-Relational Mapping frameworks and Query builder.
- I am well versed in using ReactJs with antdesign which is a component library

Certifications

- Udemy The complete javascript course 2022 from zero to expert
- Udemy nodejs-the-complete-guide
- Udemy Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More The Complete Bootcamp 2021
- Udemy Fundamentals of database engineering
- Udemy SQL the complete introduction to sql programming

Projects

Web Application

- E-commerce web and mobile application / Final year research.
- Dayk Application / API and admin dashboard development.
- Real Estate management system for miransafiny Co.
- Real Estate management system for MPC Co.
- Implemented RESTful API and admin dashboard for dar application
- Implemented RESTful API for Alagarat which is a subscription platform for real estate companies.
- Implemented RESTful API for service application which is <u>pesha.krd</u>
- Implemented RESTful API and admin dashboard for diwan lounge application
- Implemented RESTful API and admin dashboard as a full stack for car shop management system.

Websites

- HITEX website <u>hitex.tech</u> / Backend developer
- Lalav website lalav.com / Backend developer
- Dasfood website <u>dasfood.com</u> / Backend Developer.
- Hillstone website <u>hillstone.com</u> / Backend Developer
- MCT website mctirag.com / Backend Developer
- Kavin group website kavin-group.com / Backend Developer
- Avi health website avihealth.org / Backend Developer
- Lumark website <u>lumark-agency</u> / Backend Developer
- Blueprint website blueprint-campus.com / Backend Developer
- Miransafiny website miransafiny.com / Backend Developer

Languages

Kurdish (Native) English (Intermediate) Arabic (Basic)